<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<addon id="service.oppokodibridge.v4" name="OppoKodiBridge v4 (CEC)" version="4.3.0" provider-name="skull-01">
  <requires>
    <import addon="xbmc.python" version="3.0.0"/>
  </requires>
  <extension point="xbmc.service" library="service.py"/>
  <extension point="xbmc.addon.metadata">
    <summary lang="en_GB">Experiment: no-blip OPPO playback with pure, spec-legitimate HDMI-CEC switching (no IR, no spoofing).</summary>
    <description lang="en_GB">OppoKodiBridge v4 is a fork of OppoKodiBridge v3 that keeps v3's playercorefactory handoff (Kodi routes disc content to an external OPPO player, so there is no pre-play "blip") but switches the TV using ONLY legitimate HDMI-CEC. The OPPO grabs its HDMI input via its OWN One-Touch-Play, forced by power-cycling the OPPO (it only asserts active source on a power-ON transition); Kodi reclaims its input by re-asserting its OWN active source. There is deliberately NO IR blaster and NO CEC injection / spoofed initiator (which corrupts the shared bus). The trade-off is the ~20-24s OPPO power-cycle on every handoff, accepted in exchange for zero extra hardware and a clean bus. Installs alongside v2 and v3 (different add-on id) for direct comparison. The OPPO HTTP API is community-reverse-engineered, not an official protocol.</description>
    <platform>all</platform>
    <license>MIT</license>
    <source>https://github.com/skull-01/OppoKodiBridge-v4</source>
    <news>4.3.0 -- Zero-config NAS detection, a Setup &amp; tests capability suite, and a correctness sweep. DETECTION (all default-safe -- a typed setting stays AUTHORITATIVE and is never overridden): auto-detect the OPPO export root (path_to) from its own NFS share list when path_to is left blank (#11); a "Detect the Kodi path prefix from Kodi's sources" button to fill path_from on demand, Kodi-side only (#10); ISO and BDMV playback capability-check buttons that wake the OPPO and report every playback flag it raises (#12/#13); and a new oppo_mount setting to override the /mnt mount directory -- default nfs1 keeps the proven /mnt/nfs1 path byte-for-byte, since the OPPO API can't report the real mount point (#14). The path_from auto-detect (4.1.7's #9) now anchors at the BROADEST share-root source so it pairs correctly with the export root instead of mis-anchoring on a nested source (#16). SWEEP FIXES: the Ping test now OREMOTE-wakes the sleeping :436 app API before probing, so a present-but-idle OPPO no longer shows a false UNREACHABLE (#29); on a give-up the orchestrator sends a best-effort STOP so a slow or auto-healed play is not left running while Kodi reclaims the TV (#28); a long PAUSE now has its OWN bounded watch budget so the TV is not reclaimed out from under a paused disc, while the watch still ALWAYS terminates (#30); the first-run wizard's "cannot reach" dialog shows the RESOLVED IP actually pinged, not the typed one (#31). Two independent adversarial audit rounds vetted the build -- a HIGH monitor-termination regression and a share-root parser false-positive were caught and fixed; residuals are low and contained (a wrong auto-detect fails safe: the mount is rejected and the handoff aborts before play). Default cec / nfs1 / typed-path behaviour is byte-for-byte unchanged -- ZERO regression, audited. 262 off-box tests green. Detection is SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (needs the OPPO + the NFS proxy to verify on hardware). This release also bundles the two IR bench DEV tools as separate downloads -- a Windows ZJIoT-serial console and a Raspberry Pi 4 LIRC console (dev-only, NOT part of the add-on). SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (hardware validation pending).
4.2.0 -- Pluggable TV-switch transports plus reference-parity handoff hardening. NEW: a tv_switch_method setting (none | cec | ir | lirc) selects how the TV input is switched on play/stop, behind a new strategy layer (tvswitch); the default 'cec' is byte-for-byte the existing HDMI-CEC behaviour (the OPPO's own One-Touch-Play grab plus the script.cecreclaim reclaim) -- ZERO regression, verified by an adversarial zero-regression audit. Two NEW, SEPARATE IR transports, both DEFAULT-OFF so nothing changes unless you pick them: 'ir' drives a ZJIoT serial IR module over a USB-TTL port (termios; Ugoos/CoreELEC), and 'lirc' blasts the TV's HDMI-input NEC code via ir-ctl on a Raspberry Pi 4's GPIO IR LED. Both switch the TV WITHOUT the roughly 20-24s OPPO power-cycle and WITHOUT wedging the M9207, and need no companion add-on. Capture the HDMI codes with the bench consoles under tools/ and paste them into the new IR-code settings; a tools/setup_rpi4_lirc.py provisioner prepares the Pi. HARDENING (reference-parity sweep vs emby-chinoppo-bridge): (#18) the mount/play gate now requires an AFFIRMATIVE reply, so an empty/non-JSON/timeout reply no longer counts as success and a play is never fired into a bad mount; (#19) http.client.HTTPException (which is NOT an OSError) is now caught in the OPPO HTTP and Kodi JSON-RPC paths, so a transport hiccup cannot crash mid-playback or strand the TV; (#20) the Settings CEC switch-over test is model-gated (it skips the M9207 power-cycle that wedges the unit); (#21) the playback-start grace is raised to the reference roughly 90s plus a bounded one-shot ISO auto-heal, so large UHD ISOs are not reclaimed mid-load; (#22) mount/play timeouts raised to 60s plus a bounded transient retry on idempotent reads, cutting false handoff failures on a slow/fragile proxy. 227 off-box tests green; each theme independently re-audited (a deep zero-regression fan-out on the tvswitch refactor). The IR transports are SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (no hardware) and ship default-off; the CEC path is unchanged. SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (hardware validation pending).
4.1.7 -- Auto-detect the Kodi path prefix (path_from) from Kodi's OWN video sources, so the NAS path mapping no longer has to be typed by hand. The typed "Kodi path prefix" stays AUTHORITATIVE: whenever it maps the file being played it is used as-is (no override, no per-play Kodi call), because it is paired with the OPPO export root at the same depth. Only when it is blank or does NOT match the file does the handoff ask Kodi for its configured video sources (Files.GetSources, over the same localhost JSON-RPC the CEC reclaim already uses) and longest-prefix-match the played file against them to fill path_from -- boundary-safe (a sibling share like Super3Share-4K never mis-matches Super3Share), multipath:// sources expanded, and a source equal to the played path or a bare host is skipped so it can never strand a mappable file. Toggle: "Auto-detect the Kodi path prefix" (NAS path mapping, default ON). Detection is Kodi-side only (no OPPO contact), best-effort, and never disturbs a correctly-typed setup. Detects path_from ONLY -- path_to (the OPPO export root) still needs the on-device probe. 124 off-box tests green, independently audited (5-lens adversarial re-audit; two highs found and fixed, then a clean recursion pass). SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (hardware validation pending).
4.1.6 -- First-run setup wizard. Guided setup (Settings -> Setup &amp; tests -> "Run the first-run setup wizard", and auto-popped once on first run): pick the OPPO model; set + PING the IP (won't proceed if unreachable); M9205 runs a CEC grab+reclaim test, M9207 goes straight to playback; then play an ISO and a BDMV on the OPPO so the add-on reads the OPPO's reported playback state and BEST-EFFORT detects the mount path (shown, captured only on confirm); finally a Kodi reclaim test (switch the TV to the OPPO, wait 10s, Kodi reclaims). IMPORTANT: the OPPO's playback-response format is unconfirmed, so mount-path detection is best-effort -- this first run doubles as the live probe (it shows what the OPPO reports if it can't parse a path). The wizard flow logic is unit-tested off-box; the Kodi GUI + hardware steps are NOT (verify on the device). 99 off-box tests green, independently audited. SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (hardware validation pending).
4.1.5 -- Settings trim: removed the two Advanced tuning knobs (OPPO poll interval, network timeout) -- they are now fixed internal defaults (5s poll, 4s timeout), like the other watch constants. The remaining Advanced settings (Kodi JSON-RPC port / username / password, needed for the CEC reclaim on a non-default or password-protected Kodi web server) are kept; that tab is now labelled "Kodi JSON-RPC". No playback behavior change. 90 off-box tests green, independently audited. SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (hardware validation pending).
4.1.4 -- Settings UX: the OPPO model is now the FIRST setting, and the IP field defaults from the model -- M9205 -> 192.168.10.10, M9207 -> 192.168.10.228. Picking the model fills the IP with that model's default unless you have typed a custom address (a custom IP is never overwritten); the service applies it on a model change and config.from_addon resolves it at runtime too. No functional change to playback. 89 off-box tests green, independently audited. SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (hardware validation pending).
4.1.3 -- Stop detection is now HTTP /getglobalinfo polling for EVERY model; the M9205-only verbose #SVM 3 push watch on :23 is removed entirely. This matches the proven reference (emby-chinoppo-bridge monitors purely over HTTP and never opens the OPPO's :23 verbose channel), and removes the code path implicated in the sluggish/locked IR remote. verbose_watch_until_stop and the @UPL parser are gone from oppo_http.py; monitor.watch_playback always uses the HTTP idle watch (tri-state probe + read-failure/watch-time ceilings, so it can never hang). oppo_model now gates ONLY the play-side TV grab (M9207 skips the grab); stop detection is identical for all models. 86 off-box tests green, independently audited. SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (hardware validation pending).
4.1.2 -- Model-gate the OPPO CEC grab (symmetry with the stop monitor). Previously the grab (a #POF-&gt;#PON power-cycle so the OPPO grabs the TV via its own One-Touch-Play) fired on every play whenever grab_tv_on_play was on, REGARDLESS of model; oppo_model only gated the stop-monitor transport. On the M9207 Plus / UDP-203 clone that power-cycle is a no-op AND harmful -- its #PON does not power on, while the #POF sleep wedges the unit (the sluggish/locked IR remote). Now the grab is gated by cec.grab_supported: the M9207 skips it entirely (regardless of grab_tv_on_play) and the TV is switched to the OPPO input manually; the M9205 still grabs. Selecting oppo_model=M9207 is now the single knob -- you no longer also have to turn off grab_tv_on_play. oppo_model now gates BOTH the stop-monitor transport and the TV grab. 93 off-box tests green, independently audited. SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (hardware validation pending).
4.1.1 -- Bug-sweep fixes (adversarially audited; follow-up to 4.1.0). (1) The M9205 verbose #SVM 3 stop-watch could spin forever holding the :23 socket when the device streamed chatter without a recognised @UPL stop token -- the prime suspect for the sluggish/locked IR remote -- because its HTTP idle cross-check fired only while the push stream was quiet and it had no absolute time ceiling; the watch now runs the HTTP cross-check on a wall-clock cadence (ending after idle_confirmations consecutive confirmed-idle reads, so a transient blip never causes a premature mid-playback reclaim) and enforces a max_watch_seconds ceiling. (2) A loose .bdmv index file NOT under a BDMV/ folder caused the handoff to NFS-mount the .bdmv FILE's own path (which hard-crashes the OPPO) and play the bare mount root; disc_folder now returns the directory that CONTAINS the index file. (3) Mount/play success checks used identity 'is False', which missed loosely-typed non-bool device replies (0 / "false"); added reply_failed() coercion at all three sites. (4) The playercorefactory rule now also matches a root-level BDMV/VIDEO_TS segment, in lockstep with the runtime classifier. 90 off-box tests green; each fix independently re-audited. SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (hardware validation pending).
4.1.0 -- Reference-aligned the play + monitor paths (to the proven emby-chinoppo-bridge) and simplified model handling. ISO now sends STP + ~4s settle before /playnormalfile (previously sent before BDMV); BDMV/VIDEO_TS sends NO STP and starts via /checkfolderhasBDMV, with a /playnormalfile fallback if that reports failure. Stop detection is now model-aware: the M9207 Plus / UDP-203 is watched over HTTP /getglobalinfo ONLY and never opens the #SVM 3 verbose socket on :23 (the prime suspect for that clone's sluggish/locked IR remote during playback); the M9205 keeps the instant #SVM 3 push watch (+ HTTP fallback). Dropped the M9207 export-root/sub-path NFS mode -- ALL models now mount the file's folder and play the bare leaf (the M9205/reference layout), and oppo_model only selects the stop-monitor transport now. 81 off-box tests green, each change independently audited. SOFTWARE-VERIFIED ONLY (not yet validated on hardware); the M9207 NFS change reverses 0.4.3 -- if disc/ISO playback is rejected at the mount step on a UDP-203 clone, the previous export-root layout can be restored from git history.
4.0.0 -- Renamed the add-on from v3 to v4: new id service.oppokodibridge.v4 and name "OppoKodiBridge v4 (CEC)", so it installs as a distinct add-on alongside v2 and v3 for direct A/B/C comparison. Carries over the pure-CEC handoff pipeline (detector/handoff/cec/monitor/orchestrator) from 3.1.0; also scopes disc detection to ISO/BDMV/VIDEO_TS and now DERIVES the playercorefactory routing rules from the same constants the runtime classifier uses, so the generated XML and is_handoff_target cannot drift apart (HD-DVD/HVDVD_TS is left to Kodi -- the OPPO cannot play it anyway). 75 off-box tests green.
3.1.0 -- OppoKodiBridge v3 adopts pure HDMI-CEC switching. v3.0.0 switched the TV with a Broadlink IR blaster; this release replaces that with legitimate CEC (the OPPO grabs its HDMI input via its OWN One-Touch-Play on a #POF-&gt;#PON power-cycle; Kodi reclaims via libCEC SetActiveSource -- no IR, no CEC injection) and brings the modular detector/handoff/cec/monitor/orchestrator pipeline with 73 off-box tests. It defaults oppo_model to M9205 (mount the movie's OWN folder + play the bare filename) -- the NFS layout that lets disc-image .iso files loop-mount to /mnt/iso and play, verified live. The OPPO HTTP API is community-reverse-engineered, not an official protocol.
0.4.5 -- Fix the in-add-on Setup &amp; tests buttons (Ping / Control test / CEC switch-over). They all crashed before doing anything with "No valid addon id could be obtained" -- config.from_addon() called xbmcaddon.Addon() with no id, which Kodi can't resolve when a script is launched via RunScript (only the background service runs "in a normal Kodi manner"). Now passes the explicit addon id; the test fake was hardened to catch this class of bug.
0.4.4 -- Corrected the M9207 grab (hardware-tested live). The oppo_model setting now ONLY selects the NFS playback layout (M9205 = mount the file's folder + bare name; M9207 Plus / UDP-203 = mount the export ROOT + sub-path -- the part verified to work). The TV grab is the plain #POF -> #PON power-cycle for every model again: v0.4.3's #EJT-as-grab for the M9207 was WRONG -- on this clone #EJT ejects the disc tray and never grabs, and in fact NO network command can grab the TV (verified live: #POF is a sleep, #PON/#POW only ACK without powering on, and the unit fires CEC One-Touch-Play only on a full IR/remote power-on; the Kodi-side reclaim works fine). Removed the #EJT branch from power_cycle() + the desktop oppo_take_tv() and its now-pointless model selector. On the M9207 Plus switch the TV manually (or via an IR blaster) with grab_tv_on_play=false.
0.4.3 -- M9207 Plus / UDP-203 support (hardware-verified). The OPPO model setting's M9207 option now drives TWO clone-specific behaviours, confirmed live on an M9207 Plus (firmware reports UDP-203): (1) it grabs the TV with a single #EJT instead of the #POF->#PON power-cycle; (2) NFS playback mounts the export ROOT (path_to) and plays the full sub-path under /mnt/nfs1 -- e.g. mount srv/nfs/media -> play /mnt/nfs1/06pr0n/clip.mp4 -- the OPPOSITE of the M9205 model (mount the file's folder, play the bare name). handoff.play() is now model-aware; the default M9205 path is byte-for-byte unchanged. The M9207 file-play was verified end-to-end against real hardware (is_video_playing=True); the disc-folder case follows the same root-mount rule. This is why the add-on previously couldn't hand files to the UDP-203 -- its M9205-only mount-subfolder/bare-name shape was rejected every time.
0.4.2 -- OPPO model selection + an NFS doc/edge fix. New "OPPO model" setting (M9205 / M9207): the M9205 keeps the verified #POF -> #PON power-cycle to grab the TV; the M9207 clone uses a single #EJT instead (operator-reported for that clone -- on a genuine OPPO #EJT is the disc EJECT command, so this is hardware-validated by the operator, not by this code). Wired through the add-on (power_cycle), the in-app settings, and the desktop CEC Switcher (model dropdown); default M9205 = unchanged behaviour. Also corrected the PLAYING_DISCS_FROM_NETWORK guide's checkfolderhasBDMV example (it double-included the mounted folder; the code's /mnt/nfs1/&lt;disc folder&gt; form was already right) and fixed play_bdmv so a disc structure sitting at the export root sends the bare /mnt/nfs1 instead of a dangling /mnt/nfs1/. 82 off-box tests.
0.4.1 -- Second hardening sweep. A multi-agent adversarial hunt found 9 more real bugs (all in error / edge paths); all fixed + pinned by regression tests (78 total). Highlights: the HTTP stop-watcher now uses a tri-state playback probe so a transient network blip is never mistaken for a stop (no premature mid-playback TV reclaim) and is bounded by read-failure + watch-time ceilings so it can never hang and skip the reclaim; serial control maps every failure (missing termios, termios.error, bad baud, absent POSIX flags) to a non-fatal OppoError; #PON still fires when #POF fails; the guided CEC switch-over test is no longer blocked for serial-control users (and Ping reports the serial cable, not a misleading :23 UNREACHABLE); the desktop CEC Switcher surfaces save failures instead of losing settings silently, and treats a connect-then-reset OPPO as reachable.
0.4.0 -- Bug-fix sweep. An adversarial hunt found 13 real bugs, all in previously-untested branches; all fixed + pinned by regression tests (63 total). Highlights: disc-folder mapping for share-root / trailing-slash / .iso-under-BDMV; HTTP status vocabulary (unknown/no-disc tokens now read idle, so the monitor can't loop forever and miss the reclaim); a dropped :23 socket now raises OppoError instead of a raw OSError (so the reclaim and the HTTP fallback aren't skipped); writer/reader profile-path mismatch (both now masterprofile); playercorefactory.xml backup/remove is marker-guarded (never clobbers a user's own file); XML-escaped paths; serial settings wired into the UI; from_addon honours dataclass defaults for undeclared ids; .cec log tag.
0.3.0 -- Clean modular rebuild: detector / handoff / cec / monitor / orchestrator (single-responsibility). The CEC reclaim now goes straight from the orchestrator to Kodi via JSON-RPC -&gt; script.cecreclaim -&gt; CECActivateSource (no flag, no stale-flag class of bug), still single-shot and never re-asserting. New Settings -&gt; Setup &amp; tests: Ping OPPO, Control test (#QPW), and a guided CEC switch-over test. (0.2.0: explicit single-shot reclaim. 0.1.0: fork of v3, IR removed.)</news>
  </extension>
</addon>
